<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stem on Raw Thoughts</title>
    <link>https://abhaikollara.github.io/tags/stem/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stem on Raw Thoughts</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://abhaikollara.github.io/tags/stem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The &#39;Why&#39; of Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://abhaikollara.github.io/posts/2018-12-03-the-why-of-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhaikollara.github.io/posts/2018-12-03-the-why-of-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>It feels good when people appreciate your work. Usually it&amp;rsquo;s as simple as a text with a couple of 👍 or ❤️ or even sharing my previous blog post on their Whatsapp status. Little things like that go a long way in motivating people. So if you&amp;rsquo;re reading this and just remembered someone who deserves your appreciation, go ahead, send them text or shoot them an email. It means a lot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Language Barrier</title>
      <link>https://abhaikollara.github.io/posts/2018-10-21-the-language-barrier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhaikollara.github.io/posts/2018-10-21-the-language-barrier/</guid>
      <description>A general tip to anyone who is learning to code. If your English is not that strong, use a dictionary. Look up word meanings. They may have multiple definitions, but they generally point to a common idea. Understanding them goes a long way in developing an intuitive understanding of the corresponding concept.
Consider the following words and their dictionary definitions.
 iterate: to do something again and again exception : a case to which a rule does not apply class : a group sharing the same economic or social status method : a systematic plan followed in presenting material for instruction static : showing little change public : exposed to general view  If you are a programmer with sound understanding of the English language, you will immediately recognise how close these definitions are to their meaning in the context of programming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is game theory anyway ?</title>
      <link>https://abhaikollara.github.io/posts/2018-08-29-what-is-game-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://abhaikollara.github.io/posts/2018-08-29-what-is-game-theory/</guid>
      <description>There was a time when I thought game theory was a theoretical approach to designing computer games. What can I say, I was young and dumb. At least now I&amp;rsquo;m older ¯\_(ツ)_/¯.
Anyways, I&amp;rsquo;m no expert in game theory, so I won&amp;rsquo;t attempt to teach you what it is. Instead I&amp;rsquo;ll spend most of my precious blog space explaining something else - the prisoner&amp;rsquo;s dilemma. The idea is not really to give you the basic lessons in game theory (sorry) but to give a brief overview of what it is and to convince you why it makes sense to have it as a theory in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>